Hello, one of the things that everyone who comes to get health insurance
asks is
how to
get health insurance and through which channel to
get health insurance. We can
get health insurance through an agent. We can get
health insurance through banks or financial institutions. If
not, we can also
purchase health insurance directly online.
Which is the best method?
I always suggest
getting health insurance through an agent because the
only thing that is needed for health insurance is at the
time of claim and renewal. At this time, there are
chances that we or our loved ones will be hospitalized. In such a situation, it is always
better to get it through an agent. The agent will always
tell you things in a customized or personalized way and will be there to help you during the claim.
So,
you should always give priority to getting health insurance through an agent.  Now
think about whether you are taking health insurance online or through a bank. Even those who are sure that
we can coordinate it alone can
take it. Now which health
insurance is the best health insurance?
Everyone asks, I
want the best health insurance.
What should I do for it?
All health insurance is good insurance for
everyone. Some have the
benefits they need. Some may have
maternity. Some may have
OPD. Some may have
higher sum insured. Some may have a
policy without a sum insured limit. So, when you search, you
need a policy with the features you need. Select. When you search,
I compare the top three health insurance plans in India. Generally, it is
a comparison for my customers.
Today, in this video, I am going to
tell you about the
top three health insurance
plans in India: ICICI Pad Health
Elevate, Nivabupa Rusher.  3. Similarly,
HDFC Erbo Optima Secure are the
three plans that I am going to compare today in this video.
Hello,
my name is Satya Espy. I am a health
insurance advisor. My hometown is
Aluva, Ernakulam. I have been working as an
advisor in the health insurance industry since 2018.
Before moving on to the video,
let's know more about these three companies.
Nivabupa is
a stand-alone health
insurance company in India, that is, it is
a health insurance company that does only health insurance business. If we
look at their claims ratio, the
claims ratio is 96%.  This means that out of
100 claims, 96 are
passed, while four are
rejected for various reasons
.  Now, if we
look at the compliance ratio, it is the same, meaning that for every 10
claims received, 12
claims are rejected.
Nivabupa is a company that does decent business and is
one of the most innovative health insurance plans in India.   The
old name for Niwabupa is Max
Bupa.
Nivabupa has a presence in 75 countries in almost the world.  The
second
company I have chosen
is HDFC Argo.  HDFC Argo is said to be the third largest
health insurance company in India.
HDFC Argo
has a single plan, a single
flagship product,
Optima Sticker. In the last five
years, they have introduced many modifications to this single product and are giving
many unique benefits to the
policyholders in the industry. It
is a plan with a comparatively high claims ratio.
HDFC Argo's
claims ratio is 99%.
Now if you look at their compliance ratio,
it is 0.006%. That is, whenever
claims come, only those
claims are subject to compliance. The
third
plan that I suggest is ICICI Bank's
Health Elevate plan.
ICICI Lombard is the largest private general insurance company in India.  If you
look at their claims ratio, it is 93%
.  Now if we
look at the compliance ratio, it is 0.008%
.  This means that
only eight claims out of 10,000 are compliant
.  ICG Lapard's
product called Health Elevate is also a
unique product with many add-ons,
that is, a customer can
select and customize the policy according to his needs. There are
add-ons available in this plan.
We will discuss these three plans in detail. Let's see
what are the unique benefits of each plan. If we
talk about Nivarsha 3,
its most unique benefit
is Unlimited Sum Insured. When
we take a policy, everyone always
asks what is the coverage,
how much sum insured do we need,
how much limit do we need? In this
plan, we have no limit, it is an
unlimited sum insured.
So, even if you get a claim of Rs. 1 crore, it will be settled. Even if you get a
claim of Rs. 2 crore, it will be settled. No matter
how many times it comes, it will be
settled. The
sum insured is unlimited.
Nivba's Reassurance 3 is a plan that is coming. It is a unique
benefit. It is
a technique or
a feature that no one has brought in the industry yet. Nivbupa's Resha 3 Oil is
coming. Now if we look at the plan called Health Elevate by ICICI Bank,
a unique benefit that I have seen is Power
Booster, which means that every year, whether we
claim a cumulative bonus of 100% or
not, we will continue to get 100% of the sum.
Now there
is another add-on called Infinite Care.
We
can use any claim up to unlimited sum.
So, these two unique benefits have been introduced in ICICI Bank.
Now if we look at HDFC Ergo Optima Secure in the industry, it is
Double
X coverage. If we take a policy of 10 lakhs,
we will get 20 lakhs in the first year itself.  Just
like other companies say, you can get coverage
as a cumulative bonus for the next year or
as a lump sum bonus for the next year.
That's not a word. In the first year itself,
we get double sum insured. Not only that,
but also the
unlimited rider HDS is
now available to us. So
these are the
unique selling points
or unique features of these three policies.
The most attractive
features are these three.
Now,
what are the basic limits and
what are the features and
coverages that come with it? Let's see. If we
talk about room rent in the basic features, in HDFC's
Optima Secure and
Nivabupa's Reassurance 3.
plan, we have no limit on room rent,
but in the
plan called ICCI Lampard's Health Elevate, there is no limit on single private
There is a limit called IC Room, but
we can change it using the rider. Now if we
take the matter of sum assured,
we can get sum assured up to Rs. 10 lakh to Rs. 1 crore.
HDFC Ergo is available.
Similarly,
unlimited sum assured option is available up to Rs. 10 lakh to Rs. 2 crore in ICICI
Lombard.
After talking about the unique benefit of Resurrect 3, it has unlimited sum assured. There is
no sum assured limit of Rs. 10 lakh or Rs. 15 lakh. It
comes with unlimited sum assured. Now if we look at the sub-limits,
we do not get sub-limits in any of these three plans.
Everything is covered up to Rs. 100 up to the sum assured. If we
look at the consumables,
HDLC Ergo is already inbuilt.
We will cover consumables.
Consumables include PP kits,
injection needles, and things like that, including the
patient's food. In
ICI Lampard and Nivabupa's Research 3,
we now cover consumables as an add-on.
We cover all types of consumables 100%. If we
take the case of pre-post hospitalization, that is, the expenses
before being admitted to the hospital and
post-hospitalization, the
outpatient expenses after being discharged.
Both of these are the maximums in all three
policies.
HDFC Argo pre-hospitalization is 60 days, and
post-hospitalization is 180 days.
This is the same as
Nivabupa Rusha 3. There is only a slight difference.
ICC Lampard's Health
Lift plan comes with
90 days for that.  Now, if we talk about pre-existing disease coverage, which can be given for 180 days pre-hospitalization and
180 days post-hospitalization,
we all know that if we
have an already existing disease and we declare it and accept it, then
normally, the
waiting period in all health insurance policies is three years. In these three
policies,
we do not have a
waiting period for existing health conditions. But for some
lifestyle illnesses, such as asthma, blood pressure, cholesterol,
diabetes,
we get day one coverage in ICC Lombard, and
similarly,
we get day one coverage in HDFC Ergol.
Now,
as another benefit in Nivabupa, I will tell you
or what is unique is that
they
provide day one coverage for about 142 conditions.  They provide day one coverage for 142 illnesses
or 142 pre-existing
conditions.
They provide day one coverage for rheumatoid arthritis. They provide day one coverage for varicose veins. This is the same
policy that provides day one coverage for all lifestyle illnesses that are common in the current era. But all of this is
subject to the decision of the underwriter.
Sometimes it is
possible that it may turn into a waiting period. It depends on our
criticality. Now let's see how the
waiting periods are in these three policies. The
normal
waiting periods are the same. Only accidents will be covered for the first 30
days. For the
first
two years, diseases that come slowly, such as
kidney stones, piles, hernia, etc.,
we will have to wait for two years.
Even the Nivabupa Rusher 3 is the same.  ICC Rapid's
health lift
also has a rider that allows us to reduce it to one year.
Now let's see what other unique
features or other add-ons are available.
HDFC
Argo is offering maternity as an add-on.
After the years, we
can
cover maternity. Maternity will be covered in a sub-limit of 1 lakh or 2 or 3 lakh. It will also be within that. Newborn baby coverage will also be available. Maternity will be covered in the third year, that is, after
paying two premiums, we
will be able to cover maternity after the second year.
Similarly, in ICICI and Lombard,
we can cover maternity in the same way. Maternity will be covered in the same
sub-limit. Maternity will be
covered after two years.
The third level, Ration 3, is
another thing that is coming up.  What is the
Lock the Clock benefit? If you
say Lock the Lock, the
premium will
remain fixed until you claim it. Researcher 3. We have
four variants available. Out of those four
variants, there will be
only the variant called Black or the
variant called Elite.
I suggest it because in the
variant called Black,
we have no limit on room rent. In the
variant called Elite, there is also a limit
called Single Private AC Room Rent. In the
variant called Select or Classic below that, we can
only take wardroom or general rooms.
So,
I do not suggest these two plans.
Another thing that everyone pays attention to while taking health insurance is the
premium.  Let's see how the premiums for these three policies are calculated
.   If
you take Niwoopa's research 3., an
unlimited sum is insured.  The
premium we pay for that is
Rs. 14,965.  Now, in the policy called Health Elevate by ICICI Bank,
we get a premium of 10 lakhs for
an individual. I am talking about the premium for a 30-year-old
individual
.  That will cost us 11,465
rupees.  On the other hand, if we take out a policy of Rs
10 lakh for a 30-year-old individual with HDFC Argola, the
premium will be Rs 124.
All of this is Zone One Premium.  Most of
these three companies, if we are zone two,
zone three or zone five, now Babupay,
we calculate the premium in zone five,
so the
premium may be comparatively less for a
person living in Kerala.
What is the specific benefit that NRIS gets in this policy? If
everyone taking the policy is an NRI,
HDFC Argola has a 40 percent discount. You just have to pay
40% less from the normal premium,
that is, if the premium is Rs. 1 lakh, you only have to
pay Rs. 6000 to reduce that amount.
Now, if Nivbupa's Reshare 3.Oil, if
everyone is an NRI, then you
get a 15 percent discount. If it
is in ICICI Lombard, we
only
need to have someone be an NRI. We get a 25% discount in ICC Lombard. In
ICICI Lombard, we
get another feature,
according to the civil score of the proposer.  You can get a discount of up to 15%
.  All three of these policies are
policies that NRIS can choose and
offer discounts to NRIS
.  You just need to select the features you need according to your budget,
add-ons and see if the
hospitals near your home have
cash on these policies. To
purchase these policies and
to know more information like this,
you can contact me directly. If you have
any doubts about these policies, you
can comment in the comment box below. You
can contact me directly on the number given below.
Follow Finsiksha for more videos like this and more health insurance information
.